A Guide to the James Whitcomb Riley Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7133-p
James Whitcomb Riley Collection 188?-1910, n.d.
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7133-p
ca. 29 items
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase [1972 August 16] 1972 September 1
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Poem, "A Bedouin", n.d.; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, "Cassander" w/autograph corr., TMs, 3 p.
  - Poem, "Eros", n.d.; AMs, 2 p.
  - Poem, "The Funniest Thing in the World" certified, 1971 October 20, by Lesley Payne, n.d.; AMs, 1 p.
  - Poem, "Gretchen" [previous titles: "Katrine," "Gudrune," and "Wilhemina"], AMsS, 1 p.
  - Early and later version of poem "The Gudewife", 2 AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, "He Called Her In", n.d.; AMsS, 5 p.
  - Poem, "Iry and Billy and Jo", AMs, 1 p.
  - Poem, "Little Johnt's Christmas", n.d.; AMs, 4 p.
  - Poem, "The Lost Path", n.d.; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem beginning, "Nobody on the Old Farm...", n.d.; AMsS, 4 p.
  - Poem, "Old Man" [last 2 l. in 7133-r], n.d.; AMs (incom.), 3 p.
  - Poem beginning, "Out on the margin...", n.d.; AMs, 1 p.
  - Poem, "Pan", n.d.; AMs, 1 p.
  - Poem, "Robert Burns", n.d.; AMs, 2 p.
  - Poem, "Someday", n.d.; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem, "The Soo-Burbs", n.d.; AMsS, 2 p.
  - Early and later version of poem, "Thoughts on the Late War", 2 AMsS, 1 p. and 2 p.
  - Poem, "Tired", n.d.; AMsS, 4 p.
  - Poem, "When Age Comes On", n.d.; AMsS, 1 p.
  - Poem beginning, "When our baby died...", n.d.; AMs (incom.), 1 p.
  - Poem, "When Maimie Married" w/AMs of draft of untitled poem on verso of second leaf, 188?; AMs, 2 p.
- Letters
  - Albert Beveridge to James Whitcomb Riley, [1902 Nov 28]; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Albert Beveridge to James Whitcomb Riley, [1905 Dec 14]; ALS, 3 p. w/env
  - Albert Beveridge to James Whitcomb Riley, [1906 Jun 12]; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - Albert Beveridge to James Whitcomb Riley, 1907 Nov 5; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Albert Beveridge to James Whitcomb Riley, [l910 Oct 30]; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Albert Beveridge to James Whitcomb Riley, Nov 9; ALS, 1 p. w/env
- Drawing
  - "Old John Henry" by James Whitcomb Riley, n.d.; Pencil drawing